Now that you've got your ROS environment variables in place,
现在 你的 ROS 环境变量已经就位
you're ready to run some turtlesim nodes.
你可以运行一些 turtlesim 节点了
So let's jump right into this.
好的 我们马上开始
The first thing you're going to need to do is start the ROS master process.
首先 你需要开启 ROS 主进程
To do this, all you need to do is run the command roscore.
具体操作很简单 只需运行 roscore 命令即可
And there we go.
好了
We've been hit with a wall of text ending with the line 'started core service'.
我们看到了满屏幕的文本 最后一行说 started core service
You don't need to worry about all the detail printed on
不用理会控制台上的这些细节
the console as none of it is really relevant to us right now.
因为它们目前和我们并不相关
As long as you don't see any colorful red text
只要没有红色文本
disclaiming that there is an error, you're good to go.
表示存在错误 就没有问题
Now that the master process is running,
现在 主进程正在运行中
you'll be able to run nodes.
你可以运行节点了
The first node that you're going to run is the turtlesim node itself.
你要运行的第一个节点是 turtlesim 节点
To run the node, you'll want to open a new terminal and execute the rosrun command.
要运行这个节点 你需要打开新的终端窗口 并运行 rosrun 命令
The first parameter you'll be passing to the rosrun command is turtlesim,
你要传递给 rosrun 命令的第一个参数是 turtlesim
the name of the ROS package containing the turtlesim nodes,
包括 turtlesim 节点的 ROS 包的名称
and turtlesim_node which is the name of
以及 turtlesim_node 这是你希望运行的
the node executable residing in the package that you wish to run.
包中的可执行节点的名称
And there you have it, you're running the simulator and
好了 你正在运行仿真器
you've got a little turtle waiting to be commanded around the window.
窗口边有一个小乌龟 你可以向其发送命令
To command the turtle to move,
要命令乌龟移动
you must run another node,
你必须运行另一个节点
the turtle teleop node.
Turtle teleop 节点
Once again, you'll need to open another terminal window.
同样地 你需要打开另一个终端窗口
And you'll run the same command you ran a moment ago
然后运行和刚才一样的命令
with the exception of the node executable name; rosrun turtlesim, our package name,
但是可执行节点的名称不同 rosrun turtlesim 包的名称
and turtle_teleop_key, the name of the node executable you wish to run.
Tuttle_teleop_key 你希望运行的可执行节点名称
If you ever forget the name of the package or node that you
如果你忘记了想运行的包或节点的名称
wish to run tab completion can be helpful.
可以使用 Tab 完成功能
So, let me go ahead and backspace.
好的 我们开始 退格
Let's say I don't know the node name,
假设我不知道节点名称
but I know that it starts with turtle,
但我知道名称开始部分是 turtle
and then I hit tab tab.
接下来 双击 Tab 键
I see that the turtlesim package has
我可以看到 turtlesim 包有
two nodes that start with the word turtle: There's turtlesim_node,
两个节点是以 turtle 开始的： 有一个是 turtlesim_node
the node that we just ran,
我们刚刚运行的节点
and then there's turtle teleop key,
第二个是 turtle telecop key
the node that we're trying to run.
我们准备运行的节点
So rosrun turtlesim, turtle teleop key.
好的 rosrun turtlesim、turtle teleop key
Now the turtlesim teleop node is running.
现在 turtlesim teleop 节点正在运行
With the turtle teleop console selected,
选择了 turtle teleop 控制台后
you can use the arrow keys to drive the turtle around the virtual world.
你就可以使用箭头命令乌龟在虚拟世界移动了
Let's give this a try.
我们试试看
Yep. And there we go.
好 好了
We're now ready to begin investigating the turtlesim coms.
现在 我们可以开始学习 turtlesim 的通信了